

About me

A business-focused data scientist with experience in health care and financial institutions. I design θ develop data science products to help clients increase profitability and improve customer experience.

Contact

Phone: +1 (514)-688-9875 email: hjasmar@outlook.com LinkedIn

Education

M.Sc. Mathematics and statistics (University of Quebec in Montreal) 2022.

 Developing a new statistical algorithm calculating the probability of finding a matching donor based on In/compatible HLA epitopes in kidney transplantation.

B.Sc. Mathematics and Statistics (University of Quebec in Montreal) 2018.

Skills

R & Shiny (Tidyverse, tidyquant, ggplot2, e1071, plotly, knitr ...etc.)
Python (Numpy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, Keras, Pytorch, Tenserflow, matplotlip)
SAS, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript
Prediction and Classification
Time series Forecasting
Customer Segmentation
Statistical inference, Survival analysis
Nonparametric methods

JENNAT LAMSATFI

DATA SCIENTIST & Web Developer

Experience

Data Scientist

BSMD Desjardins

1 2021 - Present

Building Al-based systems capable of machine learning to provide the necessary tools to accelerate and bring greater precision to audit processes.

- Building Machine learning models for fraud prediction and classification of sites in terms of performance.
- · Anomaly detection models.
- Set up the structure and the work methodology for the data science team.
- Recruitment of analysts, junior data scientists and interns.
- Set up the road map of data science projects in audit (Credit, insurance and reseau des caisses).

Mathematician - Statistician

Statistics Canada

1 2020 - 2021

Sample production for the monthly Labor Force Survey.

- Generate the sample list for the monthly production across Canada for the Labor Force Survey.
- Create scenario scripts to test the behavior of the upcoming new platform for the Labor Force Survey.
- Work closely with the developer team to fix bugs.

Teaching Assistant

UQAM - University of Sherbrooke

₁ 2015 - 2019

Prepare and explain the labs for undergrade students. Prepare revision labs for exams and correct homework and exams.

Internships

Consultant in Statistics / Biostatistics

CRCHUS (Sherbrooke) SCAD (UQAM) 2017 - 2019

Understand client (researchers, doctors and students) needs, realize the statistical analysis and produce the study reports with interpretation of the results. Program custom functions and algorithms for clients.